Nick Skotarenko Software developer

Executive Summary

- 6 years of experience developing: software, web-applications, websites.
- Main skills (active skills set):
- Experience in code design
 - Team and result oriented player, learning skills.
 - SCRUM projects experience (planning, demo, retrospective etc.)
 - · Good team communication skills.
- Unit test practical experience (JUnit, Mockito).
- I worked by different processes and methodologies, use of OOP, working by TDD and OOD, refactoring during coding, research ability, working by scrum.
- Quick learner, analytical mind.

Technical Skills

Skill Category	Skill List	
Programming Languages	Java SE	
Technologies	OOP, TDD, OOD	
RDBMS	MySQL, Oracle	
Web	JavaScript, HTML, CSS	
Operating Systems	Windows; Linux: Ubuntu, Mint;	
Development Tools	IDEA, Eclipse, SQL Developer, WebStorm, TOAD	
Other	Spring: Boot, Framework, Security Data, JDBC, Log4J, JQuery, JSP, XML, Tomcat, FlexBox, Bootstrap, SonarQube, Git, Kafka, Impala, HBase, Hadoop, Swagger	

Foreign Language Skills

Language	Written	Spoken
English	Upper-Intermediate	Upper-Intermediate
French	Intermediate	Intermediate

Training Programs

Program Name: Luxoft Java Training(Java SE)

Date(s) Attended: January 2014

Status: Completed.

Program Name: Vertex Java Training(Java SE)

Date(s) Attended: June 2016
Status: Completed.

Education

Institution: Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv

Qualification(s): Engineering and mathematics, Mathematics faculty

Professional Experience

Company: Epam (Prague)

Duration: 2018 (January) – Present

Role: Java Developer

Responsibilities: • developing of web application

· developing server side and client side;

bug fixingre-factoring

re-factoring and developing architecture of application

demo and delivery of application

Technologies: Java, JUnit, JDBC, Spring, JMS, Oracle, Cloud (internal), AutoSys,

TeamCity, Tomcat

Company: Digitally Inspired

Duration: 2016 – 2018

Role: Java Developer (Full Stack)

Responsibilities: • developing of web application

developing server side and client side;

bug fixingre-factoring

Technologies: Java, JUnit, JDBC, Spring, Apache Flex, Kafka, Swagger, Oracle

Company: Vertex Academy

Duration: 2016 - 2017

Role: Coach (Java, Web)

Responsibilities: • Lead groups of "Java"

Lead groups of "Web"

Ability to explain complex things in simple languageAbility to lead a team and to lead to the desired goal

Technologies: Java, JUnit, Maven, Tomcat, HTML, CSS, Javascript, FlexBox,

Bootstrap

Company: Majorelle

Duration: 2015 - 2016

Role: Full Stack Web-developer

Responsibilities: • implement server side for website

· create commercial sites

· implement Javascript functionality

Technologies: WordPress, Woocommerce, Magento, Bootstrap, Javascript,

JQuery, PHP, HTML, CSS

Company: Smetner

Duration: 2013 - 2015

Role: Junior Java developer

Responsibilities: • web-applications development

· implement server side for website

Technologies: Spring, Tomcat, JDBC, MySQL

Contacts:

email: nick.skotarenko@gmail.com

skype: nick.skotarenko

cellphone: +380 95 000 60 12 (Ukraine)

+420 73 949 26 78 (Czech Republic)